

Łukasz Sokołowski

Software Engineer

+48 516 258 890

lukaszsokol97@gmail.com

Warsaw, Poland

Skills

- HTML5 and CSS3
- Scripting languages: JavaScript, Python, TypeScript
- Programming languages: Java, Bash, Batch
- Frameworks/Libraries: React,
 React Query, Tailwind CSS, jQuery,
 Django
- Database: Oracle SQL, PostgreSQL, PL/SQL
- Tools and technologies: REST API, JIRA, Git, Figma, WebSocket, Enterprise Architect
- Other skills: AWS, Docker, Linux,
 Data Migration, Data Analysis,
 Banking Industry Knowledge,
 Consulting IT, Graphic Design,
 Team work, Team management

Language skills

- English: proficient
- Polish: native

Hobbies & Interest

- Drawing
- Computer graphics
- Sport
- Gym
- Music

Links and Credentials



Check out my portfolio!



About me

I am a Specialist Senior at Deloitte, specializing in data migration with a focus on banking systems. I have worked on projects for major banks in the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and Australia. My responsibilities included overseeing the technical aspects of projects, where I collaborated with analysts to design, develop and implement solutions. I conducted testing across various environments (internal, SIT, UAT, PFT and final implementation on PROD) and provided both remote and on-site support during the cutover of migration processes in Australia. This role demanded constant vigilance, analysis and quick problem-solving to address unexpected issues by implementing appropriate solutions.

My daily work involves leading and mentoring the team members in technical aspects, distributing/supervising the tasks, analyzing legacy data, developing mapping processes, overseeing data migration from both business and technical perspective, creating and maintaining technical documentation, optimizing performance of migration/database processes, managing database, troubleshooting application/database backend issues, conducting reviews, debugging, refactoring of the code and automating development/deployment processes.

Experience



Deloitte Consulting S.A.

Specialist Senior (Software Engineer) | Mar 2024 - present

Worked as a:

- Lead Migration Expert on an Australian project,
- Java Developer on an UK project.



Deloitte Consulting S.A.

Consultant (Software Engineer) | Jan 2021 - Mar 2024

Involved in projects for Czech, Slovak, Hungarian and Australian banks as a Data Migration Specialist. My involvement consisted of:

- analysis of legacy data and migration process,
- analysis of business aspect of the designs,
- support during Test Runs, Dry-Runs and Go-Lives,
- · support on technical issues,
- writing/working with technical documentation,
- optimization of database/migration processes in terms of performance and design,
- · support and development of new functionalities,
- database management,
- application backend management,
- mentorship of the team members in technical aspects,
- distributing/supervising the tasks,
- mapping, bug fixing, reporting,
- debugging, refactoring and improving code,
- automation of development/deployment process Jenkins pipelines (CI/CD), Spring Boot web app (CI/CD), test data generator (Python), Bash/Batch scripts.



Falcon Brothers Autokosmetyka

Graphic designer | Jun 2022 - present

I have designed and created the vector logo, business cards, variety of: fence banners, social media banners and posters.



MR Detailing Autokosmetyka

Graphic designer/web administrator | Jul 2020 - present

I have designed and created: the vector logo, company's website, business cards, variety of: fence banners, social media banners, website banners and posters.

ARTMATIC S.C.

Intern | Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

On-site service, design of process visualisation, configuration and testing of MODBUS TCP/IP communication, programming in LAD and SCL, configuration of safety systems and time relays, testing of SCADA MAPS functions.

Education

2020 - 2022

Warsaw University of Technology

Master of Automatics, Automatics, robotics and industrial informatics

I graduated in June 2022. In my thesis, I looked into development of a teaching station communication system for remote management and monitoring, using a real-time web application. The aim of the study was to design remote communication between two workstations located in two different networks, using commonly available tools. The system was designed to replicate a real automation system with the help of a simulation and a designed web interface - referring to the broader issue of the Internet of Things.

2016 - 2020

Bialystok University of Technology Engineer of Automatics, Automatics and robotics

I graduated in March 2020. In my thesis, I looked into the design and construction of a stand for parametric vibration testing - called swing robot.

I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for realising the recruitment process pursuant to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).